Objective -

To work on an international project, contributing to my experience in Java engineering, aiming to improve English.

About me -

I am an enthusiast in technologies, software engineering, project management, and related areas. I have been working with architecture, specification, development, maintenance, and software creation for more than 12 years, contributing with Brazilian companies and institutions, developing solutions teaching computer subjects undergraduate and postgraduate courses of public and private universities. I currently work as a Senior Systems Analyst in the Department of Information Technology (UECE) and teacher of the Licentiate in Computing (UECE) course. Graduated in Computer Science from the University Center of João Pessoa (2007), MBA in Project Management (2017) and Master in Applied Computing (2011) from the State University of Ceará.

Contatos -

- +55**85**9**9614**5615 (WhatsApp)
- Fortaleza Ceará Brasil
- marcoseduardoss@gmail.com
- marcos.eduardo@uece.br
- in linkedin.com/in/marcoseduardoss
- lattes.cnpq.br/0653076998343135

English.

Reading Writing

Conversation

Skills '

Java

Agile technics with Scrum

JPA/HIbernte

Development web (JSF / Struts)

Development Web (Angular/React)

Spring Technologies

Web Services (Rest / Soap) **Development Mobile**

EJB / Jboss

Oracle/SqlServer/Postgres/MySqL

MARCOS EDUARDO

Education

Architecture of Distributed Systems

Postgraduate Degree, Pontifica Catoloca de Minas Gerais (Brazil)

Software Engineering with DevOps

Postgraduate Degree, State University of Ceará - UECE (Brazil)

Project Management

Postgraduate Degree, State University of Ceará - UECE (Brazil)

2011 **Applied Computing**

Master's Degree, State University of Ceará - UECE (Brazil)

Bachelor in Computer Science

Graduated Degree, University Center of João Pessoa - UNIPÊ (Brazil)

Experience

Software Enginner

Definition of architecture, technical leadership, analysis, and development of Softwares for DETIC/UECE (2012-2019), using agile technics with Scrum and the following Technologies or resources: Design Pattern, Java/JavaScript/TypeScript/PHP/Perl/C, PL/SQL/ PGSQL, PostgresSQL/SQLServe/Oracle/MySQL, Spring (Boot, MVC, Data, Security, Batch), Hibernate/JPA, JSF, RichFaces, PrimeFaces, BootFaces, Bootstrap, Web Service (Rest/Soap), Jersey, Angular/ AngularJS/React/PrimeNG/Bootstrap/MaterialDesign, Ireport, SVN/ GIT, GITLAB/GITHUB/BITBUCKET, CI/CD/Gitlab/Jenkins Enterprise Architect for UML modeling, ITIL, MSproject, Trello, OTRS, and others **Technologies or resources**

7 Years **University Professor**

Professor in graduate and undergraduate courses, always seeking to teach classes in the areas of systems, projects and software engineering for educational institutions Wyden/UniFanor (2010-2012), UECE (2012-2019) and Unicatólica (2013, 2018). Subjects: Software Engineering, Project Management with Scrum, System Analysis, Algorithms, Human-Computer Interaction, Database, Web Development (Java), Data Structure (C), Search and Ordering Data (C), Programming Language I (Basic Java), Programming Language II (Advanced Java) and Logic Notions

Senior Java Developer

Development, maintenance, and deployment of systems for Naja Soluções (2008) and UECE (2008-2012), using agile technics with Scrum, JSF, Junit, JBoss Server, Spring, JPA, Hibenate, SQL Server, Eclipse, SVN, Eclipse, NetBeans, Advanced JavaScript, Ext-JS and other technologies

Java Developer

Development, maintenance, and deployment of systems for TRE-PB (2005-2008) using Java technologies, Oracle SGBD, Struts, XML, SWT, Servlet, JSP, Jasper Report, ireport, HTML, Postgres, Postges, BDdesign, Oracle, NetBeans, CVS, and Jude for UML modeling

VOLUNTARY WORKS

Instructor of free extension courses of Java (Servlets, JSF, Spring and JPA) offered the students of Brazilian public institutions.

CERTIFICATIONS

- HCMP® Human Change Management Professional 2017 HCMBOK® Human Change Management Body of Knowledge- 2015
- CertifiedScrumMaster® 2013
- Sun Certified Associate for Java Platform® 2009

2021

2021

2017

2007

6 Years

4 Years

3 Years